Guide to the Rice University Early Land Deeds, Contracts and Related Records, 1830-1969 UA 222
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Early Land Deeds, Contracts and Related Records
1830-1969
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 222
35 Linear Feet (66 boxes plus oversize)
The collection contains records and printed material on the early land holdings and dealings of William Marsh Rice and the Rice Institute in 45 Texas counties and 4 Louisiana parishes. The collection also contains records and printed material concerning early Rice Institute campus construction, legal matters (including judicial settlements and statements), institutional housekeeping (including receipts and invoices from 1891-1907), and campus area property and construction.
Biographical/Historical note
William Marsh Rice was born in Springfield, Massachusetts on March 14, 1816. He was the third of ten children born to David and Patty Hall Rice. Little is known about Rice's childhood but records indicate that he worked for a while as a shopkeeper in Springfield before deciding to move to Texas in 1838.
Rice started out in business as a merchant in Houston, Texas. His first business partnership with a Barnabas Haskill was formed in 1840 but dissolved by 1842. In 1844 Rice became a commission and forwarding merchant in partnership with Ebenezer B. Nichols, a Houston businessman. By 1850 Rice's siblings began to follow him to Houston and assisted in his ventures. On June 29, 1850 Rice married Margaret Bremond whose father Paul was one of Rice's many business partners. In the census of 1860, Rice is listed as having $750,000 in real and personal property, making him one of the wealthiest men in Texas at the time.
At least 15 enslaved people were included as Rice's property in 1860. According to county deed records and newspaper advertisements, Rice purchased, sold, and accepted mortgages on enslaved people; he also attempted to recapture enslaved people who fled him. In addition to extending credit to slaveowners who leveraged enslaved people as collateral, Rice also bought and sold cotton as a substantial portion of his antebellum business. Rice served on a secession committee in Houston after the 1860 presidential election, and during the Civil War, Rice and his wife Margaret raised money for Confederate soldiers. On August 13, 1863, Margaret Rice died, possibly from cholera or yellow fever. Shortly after his wife's death, Rice went to Monterrey, Mexico and stayed there until August of 1865 when he returned to Houston. In Monterrey, Rice smuggled cotton and manufactured goods across the Texas-Mexico border. Later in the summer of 1865, he went to Massachusetts for business and did not return to Houston until 1866. On June 26, 1867 Rice married for a second time. His second wife was Julia Elizabeth Baldwin Brown, a widow and a daughter of Horace Baldwin, one of the early mayors of Houston. Elizabeth's sister Charlotte was the wife of William's younger brother Frederick.
Rice and his second wife moved to New Jersey to live with Rice's sister Charlotte and her family. Rice and his wife divided their time between New York City and New Jersey with occasional trips to Houston to oversee business. During one of the Rices' visits to Houston, he was approached by Cesar Maurice Lombardi, who was interested in building a high school in Houston. Rice had been interested in endowing an educational institute of some kind, having revised his will twice previously to include a school for needy boys, first in New Jersey, then in New York City. After the meeting with Lombardi, Rice decided to fund an institute of higher learning in Houston. On May 19, 1891 the charter for the William M. Rice Institute for the Advancement of Literature, Science and Art was incorporated in Austin, Texas. Captain James Addison Baker, William's brother Frederic, Houston businessmen Emanuel Raphael, Cesar Lombardi, James E. McAshan and Alfred S. Richardson were named as the first board of trustees.
In article two of the charter: "(t)he objects, intents, and purposes of this Institution are declared to be the establishment and maintenance, in the City of Houston, Texas, of a Public Library, and the maintenance of an Institution for the Advancement of Literature, Science, Art, Philosophy and Letters; the establishment and maintenance of a Polytechnic school; for procuring and maintaining scientific collections; collections of chemical and philosophical apparatus, mechanical and artistic models, drawings, pictures and statues; and for cultivating other means of instruction ..." The charter also required that the Institute only accept white students, which was changed in 1965. The institute was initially endowed with a promissory note for $200,000 to be paid upon Rice's death. Rice revised his will on September 26, 1896 and left the bulk of his estate to his namesake institute. During the battle over the estate two lawyers became involved with the proceedings and would end up greatly influencing the final results. Captain Baker, a trustee of the Rice Institute, served as William Rice's lawyer. Albert Patrick, the other lawyer, was hired by Orren Holt in 1898 to investigate the residency question in New York City. There Patrick met Charlie Jones, Rice's valet. The two spent a great deal of time together and slowly a plan was formed. At first it seemed that Patrick was only interested in the settlement of the contested will and was looking for any way to win. He convinced Jones, in the spring of 1900, to start poisoning Rice with mercury pills as a way to avoid a court battle. By the summer of 1900 Patrick came up with the idea to forge a will that left the majority of Rice's estate to himself and small sums to relatives and friends. The forged will was dated June 30, 1900.
On September 8, 1900 a hurricane struck the Gulf Coast and one of Rice's businesses, the Merchants and Planters Oil Company, suffered severe damage. The business manager telegraphed that they needed money for repairs and the sum was most of what Rice had available in his bank account. Patrick was worried at the loss of such a large sum of ready cash and he convinced Jones to use chloroform to kill Rice. On September 23, 1900 Rice was murdered by Jones. Patrick, in his haste to get hold of Rice's cash, tried to withdraw money from Rice's bank using a check forged by Jones right after Rice's death. The bank refused to honor the check since Patrick's name was spelled incorrectly. When calling to verify the check with Rice, the bank learned that he was dead. Since the circumstances were suspicious, the bank contacted Rice's Houston lawyer, Captain Baker.
When Baker arrived in New York City, he learned there had been a new will written up by Patrick. Baker was suspicious of the will since Rice had never notified him of any changes to the one Baker had drawn up on September 26, 1896. This suspicion led to a long and sensational trial where Patrick's version of the will was exposed as a forgery and the scheme to kill Rice was discovered. Patrick was found guilty of murder and forgery on March 26, 1902 and was sentenced to die in the electric chair. Jones, who confessed to his part of the events, ended up being released despite being the one who had actually committed the murder. Patrick's sentence was commuted to life imprisonment by the governor of New York, but eventually won a full pardon in 1912.
On February 6, 1902 Orren Holt settled the suit over Elizabeth's will for $200,000. After the trials and settlement, Captain Baker and the original Board of Trustees set about fulfilling Rice's dream to have an institute for higher learning in Houston, Texas. To guide them, the trustees chose an first president, a young mathematician and astronomer at Princeton University named Edgar Odell Lovett, who signed on as president in 1908. Lovett had earned doctorates both from the Universities of Virginia and Leipzig and had taught at Johns Hopkins, the University of Chicago, and Princeton, the most innovative American universities of the time. The trustees sent him on a worldwide tour of the "competition," where he interviewed faculty, inspected facilities, and developed an inspired vision of what might be accomplished on the plains of Texas with a blank-check charter, a generous endowment, and high ambitions. The goal was a university "of the highest grade" that kept "the standards up and the numbers down." Lovett shaped the university that Rice would become.
The Rice Institute opened on September 23, 1912, the anniversary of Mr. Rice's murder, with 77 students and a dozen faculty. An international academic festival celebrated the opening three weeks later, a spectacular event that brought Rice to the attention of the entire scholarly world. Four years later, at the initial commencement, 35 bachelor degrees and one master's degree were awarded, with the first doctorate conferred in 1918.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains records and printed material on the early land holdings and dealings of William Marsh Rice and the Rice Institute in 45 Texas counties and 4 Louisiana parishes. The collection also contains records and printed material concerning early Rice Institute campus construction, legal matters (including judicial settlements and statements), institutional housekeeping (including receipts and invoices from 1891-1907), and campus area property and construction.
Conditions Governing Access note
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Related Archival Materials note
Early Rice Institute records, 1844-1941 (bulk 1880-1916), UA 101, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University. 117 boxes. See finding aid online at http://library.rice.edu/collections/WRC/finding-aids/university-archives/early-rice-institute-papers
Index Terms
Subjects
Slavery; Universities and colleges; Business
Document Types
receipts (financial records); Maps; contracts; financial records; memorandums; deeds; architectural drawings (visual works)
Subjects (Persons)
Raphael, E.; Baker, James Addison; Rice, B.B.; Rice, Elizabeth Baldwin; Rice, William Marsh; Waldo, Wilmer, Mr.
Subjects (Corporations)
Baker & Botts; Rice University
- Series I: Rice Land Deeds, 1830-1966; 144825; 39 Linear Feet
  - Louisiana Lands and Timber, 1903-1925; 145424; 1 Linear Feet
    - Louisiana Lands and Timber, 1903-1925, 145516
      - Act of sale, Louisiana lands, 1911, 145526 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., purchase/sale of timberlands in Louisiana, 1911, 145524 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Waiver concerning timber mortgage, Louisiana lands, 1917-1918, 145525 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Various documents, Louisiana lands, 1907-1921, 145523 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
      - Balance of unpaid bonds, American Lumber Co., 1913, 145522 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 5)
      - Sale of Louisiana timber lands, 1911-1925, 145521 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 6)
      - 2nd supplemental agreement, 1914, 145520 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 7)
      - Louisiana land of Rice Land Lumber Co., 1911, 145519 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 8)
      - Copy - deed, from William M Rice and Elizabeth Baldwin Rice, 145518 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 9)
      - Vouchers/expenses, Louisiana lands, 1911, 145517 (Box 1, Folder 1, Subfolder 10)
    - Louisiana Lands and Timber, 1904-1923:, 145511
      - Meeting of Rice Institute Trustees concerning sale of Louisiana timber land, 1911, 145515 (Box 1, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Certified copy of minutes for the meeting held January 25, 1911, 145514 (Box 1, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Correspondence concerning sale of Louisiana lands, 1904-1911, 145513 (Box 1, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - Correspondence concerning Louisiana lands, 1910, 1923, 145512 (Box 1, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
    - Louisiana lands and timber, Allen Parish, 1918-1926, 145505
      - Act of sale, Allen Parish, LA., 1925, 145510 (Box 1, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Agreement for tram right-of-way, Allen and Rapides Parishes, 1918, 145509 (Box 1, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Oberlin Tract, Allen Parish, 1926, 145508 (Box 1, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Pawnee Tract, Allen Parish, 1926, 145507 (Box 1, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
      - Re-conveyance, Kinder and Northwestern Railroad to Rice Institute, 1925, 145506 (Box 1, Folder 3, Subfolder 5)
    - Sale of Land to Walter Cloud, Allen Parish, LA., 1907-1920, 145504 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Laird heirs settlement of claim of John Laird, Allen parish, LA., 1916-1923, 145503 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Rice Land Lumber Co., Louisiana land sales, leases, easements, etc., Allen Parish, LA., 1938-1965, 145494
      - Right-of-way with Industrial Lumber Co., Allen parish, LA., 1934, 145502 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
      - Right-of-way to state of Louisiana and Louisiana Highway Commission, Allen Parish, 1937, 145501 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
      - Acknowledgement of tenancy to A.B. Marcantel, 1938, 145500 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
      - Right-of-way for public road, 1953, 145499 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 4)
      - Grazing leases, 1952-1953, 145498 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 5)
      - Contract for 20 years for removal of stumps in Allen, Beauregard and Rapides Parishes, 1944, 145497 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 6)
      - Tennessee Gas Transmission Co., right-of-way agreement and damage release, 1950, 145496 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 7)
      - Lease agreements, Harmony Development Co., 1952-1965, 145495 (Box 1, Folder 6, Subfolder 8)
    - Louisiana Land and Timber, Beauregard Parish, 1913-1926:, 145482
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Will Rice lands and timber in Beauregard Parish, LA., 1923, 145493 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Indemnity bond between Long Bell Lumber Co., and Southwest Lumber Co., Beauregard Parish, 1913, 145492 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Long Bell Lumber Co., conveyance, Beauregard Parish, 1913, 145491 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Land lease, Beauregard Parish, 1921, 145490 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Merryville tract, Beauregard Parish, 1926, 145489 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 5)
      - Leases, Beauregard Parish, 1916-1918, 145488 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 6)
      - Lease, Rice Land Lumber Co. to Colfax Co., 1918, 145487 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 7)
      - Redemption deed and correspondence3 to Beauregard Parish, 40 acres, 1923-1924, 145486 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 8)
      - American Lumber Co., lease for turpentine sites, 1918, 145485 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 9)
      - Quit claim to Beauregard Parish for public road, 1919, 145484 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 10)
      - List of lands owned by Rice Land Lumber Co. in Beauregard Parish, undated, 145483 (Box 2, Folder 1, Subfolder 11)
    - Sale of land to Gulf Sabine and Red River Railroad Co. for right-of-way, 1913-1917, 1934-1935, 145481 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Donation of 160 acres of land to Beauregard Parish (Merryville) School Board, 1918-1920, 145480 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sale of 8 acres to Frank Roberts of Merryville, LA., 1913-1918, 145479 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Conveyance of land to Beauregard Parish for right-of-way for road, 1919-1928, 145478 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sale to Louisiana Highway Commission, Beauregard Parish, 1928, 1969, 145477 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Right-of-way agreement to United Pipeline Co., Beauregard Parish, 1930-1961, 145476 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Leases, Beauregard Parish, 1932-1964:, 145472
      - Chyler Gill lease from Rice Land Lumber Co. in Beauregard Parish, 1932-1951, 145475 (Box 2, Folder 8, Subfolder 1)
      - Sam T. Roberts lease from Rice Land Lumber Co. in Beauregard Parish, 1935-1936, 145474 (Box 2, Folder 8, Subfolder 2)
      - Lease to Department of Conservation of the State of Louisiana, Beauregard parish, 1937, 1962, 1964, 145473 (Box 2, Folder 8, Subfolder 3)
    - Agreements with Atlantic Refining Co., Beauregard Parish, 1940-1964, 145471 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Rice Land Lumber Co., Louisiana land sales, leases, easements, etc., Beauregard Parish, 1935-1967, 145461
      - Lease with A.B. Hauser, 1939-1955, 145470 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 1)
      - Right-of-way easement to Beauregard Electric Cooperative, 1948-1951, 145469 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 2)
      - Easement to the Kansas City Southern Railroad Co., 1940, 1966-1967, 145468 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 3)
      - Easement, etc., to the United Gas Pipeline Co., 1935, 1941, 145467 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 4)
      - General and right-of-way permit, Southern Bell, 1941-1946, 145466 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 5)
      - Lease, Louisiana Forestry Commission, 1951, 145465 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 6)
      - Acknowledgement of tenancy and pasturage leases, 1942-1967, 145464 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 7)
      - Land lease with the United States of America, 1943-1945, 145463 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 8)
      - Acknowledgement of tenancy to C.G. Wunsch, 1945-1951, 145462 (Box 2, Folder 10, Subfolder 9)
    - Rice Land Lumber Co., Louisiana land sales, leases, easements, etc., Beauregard Parish, 1947-1967:, 145455
      - Pasturage lease, tenancy and other tracts, 1946-1963, 145460 (Box 3, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Right-of-way easements, 1947-1956, 145459 (Box 3, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Title reserves, Oil Reserves Corp., 1959, 145458 (Box 3, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Pasturage lease, C.G. Wunsch, 1961, 145457 (Box 3, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
      - Pasturage lease, L.F. Grant, 1964-1967, 145456 (Box 3, Folder 1, Subfolder 5)
    - Louisiana Land and Timber, Calcasieu Parish, 1908-1929, 145444
      - Deed, W.P. Knopf to Rice Land Lumber Co., Calcasieu Parish, 1912, 145454 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Calcasieu Parish, 1918, 1929, 145453 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., lease in Calcasieu Parish, 1913, 145452 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - List of land for American Lumber Co., timber purchase, Calcasieu and Rapides Parishes 1911, 145451 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., Will Rice lands and timber in Calcasieu and Rapides Parishes, 1911-1914, 145450 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co., estimate and sale of land to Sabine Tram Co., Calcasieu Parish, 1911, 145449 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
      - Supplemental agreement, Calcasieu Parish, 1913, 145448 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 7)
      - Estimate of timber on Louisiana lands, Calcasieu and Rapides Parishes, 1911, 145447 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 8)
      - Leases, Calcasieu Parish, 1908-1911, 145446 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 9)
      - Lease, exchange of properties with Central Coal and Coke, Calcasieu Parish, 1910-1912, 145445 (Box 3, Folder 2, Subfolder 10)
    - Louisiana Land and Timber, Calcasieu Parish, 1884-1911, 145430
      - Louisiana lands, surveying, Calcasieu Parish, 1906-1908, 145443 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Sale of land to W.G. Strange, 1908, 145442 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - Standard Oil, right-of-way, 1910, 145441 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - Transfer of land to Merryville Cemetery Association, 1907-1908, 145440 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
      - Land conveyed to T.W. Davidson, 1907-1908, 145439 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 5)
      - Kinder and Northwestern right-of-way, 1910, 145438 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 6)
      - Conveyance of timber to J.M. West, 1911, 145437 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 7)
      - Sabine Tram Co., right-of-way, 1910, 145436 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 8)
      - Sale of lands in Calcasieu Parish, 1887, 1907, 1911, 145435 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 9)
      - Deed, American Lumber Co. to Rice Land Lumber Co., 1911, 145434 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 10)
      - Deeds of William Johnson, Abner Ashworth and J.S. Brice, 1907-1908, 145433 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 11)
      - Certificates and patents of land held in Louisiana, 1884-1891, 1910-1911, 145432 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 12)
      - Lease, right-of-way deed to Jasper and Eastern Railroad Co., Calcasieu Parish, 1907, 145431 (Box 3, Folder 3, Subfolder 13)
    - 27 acres to Henry and Joseph Rosteet, Calcasieu Parish, 1958, 145429 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Booklets: Act of sale and mortgage in Calcasieu Parish, 145426
      - Rice Land Lumber Co. to American Lumber Co., 1911, 145428 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Rice Land Lumber Co. to Sabine Tram Co., 1911, 145427 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Rice Land Lumber Co., Louisiana land sales, leases, easements, etc. Evangeline Parish, 1951, 145425 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Old Town Company, various counties, 145414
    - Old Town Company lot suits for collection of notes, 1910-1917, 145423 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Old Town Company lot suits for collection of notes, 1897-1922, 145422 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Tax receipts, 1875-1905, 145421 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Tax receipts, 1873-1904, 145420 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Various deeds, titles and Townsite Company lots, 1870-1912, 145416
      - Estate of A. Groesbeck, 1887, 1907, 145419 (Box 5, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Deeds or partition, various counties, 1904, 145418 (Box 5, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Lists of Town Company property, undated, 145417 (Box 5, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
    - Title papers concerning partition of Town lot properties in towns along Houston and Texas Central railroad, 1872, 1888, 1904-1919, 145415 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Texas Counties, 144826
    - Anderson County, 145411
      - Antonio Varga Survey, Anderson Co., 1908-1918, 145413 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Sale, 569 acres in Varga Survey to J.H. Stafford, Anderson Co., 1900-1923, 145412 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Bastrop County, 145404
      - A. Martinez Survey, Bastrop Co., 1899-1908, 145410 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Out of A. Martinez League to R.L. Brown, Bastrop Co., 1908, 145409 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Sale, 56 acres in A. Martinez League to Thomas Freeman, Bastrop Co., 1912-1915, 145408 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Sale, 393 acres in A. Martinez Survey to T.L. Snowden, Bastrop Co., 1908-1920, 145407 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Various deeds and title papers, Bastrop Co., 1887, 1911-1917, 145405 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - Disclaimer for land against Elgin Light and Power Co., Bastrop Co., 1911, 145406 (Box 6, Folder 7, Subfolder 1)
    - Bell County, 145401
      - Decatur Daniels Survey, Bell Co., 1830, 1850-1857, 1902-1903, 145403 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Decatur Daniels Survey, Bell Co., 1907-1908, 145402 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Bexar County, 145389
      - Lots on Camp St., San Antonio, Bexar Co., 1892, 145400 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - St. James Hotel property, San Antonio, Bexar Co., 1908-1912, 145399 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Sale, 1 lot in San Antonio to J. H. Peacock, Bexar Co., 1910, 145398 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Sale, 2 blocks in San Antonio to Ben Nathan, Bexar Co., 1927-1928, 145397 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Sale, 4 lots in San Antonio to Gus Zulmanzig, Bexar Co., 1909-1910, 145396 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Sale, 7 lots in San Antonio to Duerler Manufacturing, Bexar Co., 1908, 145395 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Sale, 8 lots in San Antonio to Mary J. Lackey, Bexar Co., 1910, 145394 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Sale, 30 blocks outside of San Antonio to J.W. Hocker, et al, Bexar Co., 1909-1911, 145393 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Sale, 13 acres in San Antonio to E.C. Wandell, Bexar Co., 1910-1913, 145392 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Sale, 60 acres in San Antonio to D.J. Allen, Bexar Co., 1909-1912, 145391 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Sale, 4 acres in San Antonio to Paul F. Hein, Bexar Co., 1916-1917, 145390 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Blanco County, 145385